wachoviadealer.com 2008-12-17

# Wachovia Dealer Services - Privacy

|  **Privacy At A Glance**

Wachovia Dealer Services1 is dedicated to protecting your privacy and providing you with the highest level of service.  We want you to understand how we gather and may share customer information at Wachovia, the choices you have, and how we protect that information in everything we do.

 **You Have Choices**

  * You may direct us not to contact you for marketing purposes by: 
    * Telephone
    * Direct mail
    * E-mail.
  * You may direct us not to allow Wachovia companies to share or use information about you in two ways: 
    * Do not share, with other Wachovia companies, credit information about you that we receive from you or others; and
    * Limit Wachovia companies from marketing their products and services to you based on credit or transaction information about you that they receive from other Wachovia companies ( _this option is available beginning October 1, 2008, and is fully described in the section below titled "Your Choice to Limit Use of Information for Marketing"_ ).

 **How to Reach Us to Exercise Your Choices**

  * Call Wachovia Dealer Services at 800-289-8004, Monday - Friday from 5 a.m. to 7 p.m. PT.

 **How We Protect Customer Information**  
Keeping financial information secure is our responsibility and our commitment to you.  

  * We protect customer information through physical, electronic, contractual and procedural measures that comply with or exceed applicable laws and standards.
  * We train our employees to protect customer information and only authorize access for employees who we believe have a business need for that information. Employees are held accountable by Wachovia's Code of Conduct and Ethics to properly protect customer information.
  * We maintain policies and procedures that provide for the proper physical security of workspaces and records.
  * We require contractors and other companies that provide services on our behalf to protect information, and we prohibit those companies from using it for any other purpose. We only provide them with information that we believe is necessary to fulfill their responsibilities or to provide a financial service to you.
  * Protecting information about our customers online is an essential part of our service to you. For more information on our Internet Security and Privacy practices, please visit wachoviadealer.com/privacy.

If you believe you are a victim of fraud or identity theft, please contact us at 1-888-647-3648 for assistance.

 **The section above is a summary. It is important that you read the rest of this Privacy Statement for a more detailed explanation of our privacy practices.**

 **How We Gather Customer Information**  
We gather information about you to help us to better understand your financial needs and to provide you with more personalized and efficient service.

The information we gather comes from a variety of sources, including:

  * Information you provide to us (such as name, address and telephone number).
  * Information about your transactions with Wachovia Dealer Services (such as account balance and payment history).
  * Information we receive from credit reporting agencies and other companies and agencies (such as your credit history).

 **Sharing Customer Information Within Wachovia Corporation**  
Wachovia Corporation includes several related companies. These companies operate in a variety of business lines, such as banking, credit cards, consumer loans, insurance, securities and others. We may share customer information about you among the companies that make up Wachovia Corporation, including:

  * Information based on your transactions with us (for example, information that we would collect about your loan accounts and contact information (such as your name and address).
  * Credit information received from you or others (such as information from your credit application or your employment or credit history) to evaluate your eligibility for various financial services (for example, a home equity loan at a special rate).

You may tell us not to share credit information with other Wachovia companies.* For more information, see the section below entitled, "Your Privacy Choices at Wachovia."

 **Sharing Customer Information Outside of Wachovia Corporation**  
We do not provide customer information to companies outside of Wachovia Corporation, except as outlined below. You do not need to request this confidentiality - it is our standard practice.

In order to serve your needs, we may provide all of the information we gather to:

  * Companies that perform business operations for us (such as statement or coupon book printing).
  * Companies that act on our behalf to market our services, or financial institutions with whom we have entered into a joint marketing agreement in order to provide you with valuable financial products and services.*
  * Others as permitted or required by law (such as to protect against fraud or in response to a subpoena).

Our policies for sharing customer information, both within and outside of Wachovia as described above, also apply to all of the information we have gathered about former customers of Wachovia.

 **How We Use Customer Information**  
The customer information we gather helps us to better understand your financial needs and to provide you with superior service by offering the right services at the right time. We may use the information among Wachovia companies and other authorized entities, for the following purposes, among others:

  * To protect your accounts from unauthorized access or fraud.
  * To provide you with the products and services you requested.
  * To service your accounts.
  * To inform you about financial products and services that may be of interest to you.

 **Your Privacy Choices at Wachovia**  
Because we recognize that you may wish to limit the ways in which we contact you for marketing purposes, we offer the following options. You can choose not to be contacted for marketing purposes by:

  1. Telephone
  2. Direct Mail
  3. E-mail

You also have choices about how credit information about you is shared within Wachovia. You may choose the following options:

  4. Do not share credit information about me that you receive from me or others among Wachovia companies.
  5. Limit Wachovia companies from marketing their products or services to you based on credit or transaction information about you that they receive from other Wachovia companies. ( _this option is available beginning October 1, 2008 and is fully described in the section below titled “Your Choice to Limit Use of Information for Marketing”_ ).

 **If you are comfortable with the ways in which we contact you currently, there is no need to indicate your preferences. To discuss your options, inform us of a preference, or provide us with feedback, call us at 800-289-8004, Monday - Friday from 5 a.m. to 7 p.m. PT or visit us on the web at** **wachoviadealer.com/privacy** **.**

Whatever your preferences, we will honor your wishes and respect your privacy. Your preferences will remain in effect until you tell us otherwise. You do not need to notify us if you have already indicated your preferences to us. If you contact us, we will assume your preferences apply to you only - unless you tell us that they also apply to other individuals listed on your accounts.

Please note that we are committed to providing you with superior service. We may contact you to resolve a problem or to service your accounts even if you have asked us not to contact you for marketing purposes. For example, if we notice unusual activity on your account, we may contact you to verify you authorized the activity. If you choose not to be contacted by direct mail for marketing purposes, you will continue to receive the marketing information that accompanies your usual account mailings and statements.

 **How to Protect Yourself**  
At Wachovia, we're committed to customer protection, which includes protecting personal information about you as well as providing you with ways to protect yourself. We recommend that you follow these security measures to protect and help prevent potential misuse of personal information about you:

  * Protect and properly dispose of your account records.
  * Do not share account information, passwords, user ID's, PINs, code words or other confidential information with others.
  * Do not provide confidential information by telephone to unknown callers.
  * Do not provide confidential information online unless you initiated the contact, know the party with whom you are dealing, and provide the information through a secure channel.
  * When conducting business over the Internet, always use a secure browser, exit online applications as soon as you finish using them, and make sure you have virus protection and a firewall and update them regularly.
  * Monitor your credit report for accuracy. By law, you are entitled to receive one free credit file disclosure every 12 months from each of the nationwide consumer credit reporting companies. To learn more or request a copy of your credit report, visit [annualcreditreport.com](http://www.annualcreditreport.com/)* or call 1-877-322-8228.
  * For additional information, please visit [wachovia.com/securityplus](http://www.wachovia.com/securityplus) or call us at 1-88-647-3648.

 **If You Believe You May Be a Victim of Fraud or Identity Theft**  
Contact us at 1-888-647-3648 to place holds on your accounts, obtain a free copy of Wachovia's Customer Fraud Assistance Package or for other assistance.

 **How to Limit Direct Marketing from Other Companies  
** To reduce the marketing materials you receive from companies other than Wachovia:

  1. Contact the Credit Reporting Industry's pre-screening opt out number (1-888-567-8688 or visit [optoutprescreen.com](http://www.optoutprescreen.com/))*. This should remove your name from all pre-approved credit solicitations.
  2. Add your telephone number to the National Do Not Call Registry. You may either call 1-888-382-1222 or register online at [donotcall.gov](http://www.donotcall.gov/)*. While this will stop many calls, you may still receive calls from businesses where you are a customer.

 **Maintaining Accurate Information**  
It is important to keep information about your accounts accurate and up to date. If you ever believe that our records contain inaccurate or incomplete information about you, please let us know immediately by contacting Wachovia Dealer Services at 800-289-8004.We are committed to resolving any inaccuracies as quickly as possible.

 _Credit Reporting Agencies_  
If you believe we have reported inaccurate information about your account to any credit reporting agency, please let us know in writing. Be sure to include your complete name, current address, Social Security Number, telephone number, account number, type of account, specific item of dispute and the reason you believe the information is wrong. Send your notice to: Wachovia Dealer Services - CBDRU, P.O.Box 1697, Winterville, NC 28590. We will investigate your concern and correct any inaccuracies we find. We will inform you of any actions we take.

 **If You Have Questions, Contact Us**  
We welcome the opportunity to answer any questions you may have about this statement or the safeguarding and confidentiality of information about our customers. Please visit our web site at wachoviadealer.com/privacy, or call us at 800-289-8004, Monday - Friday from 5 a.m. to 7 p.m. PT to speak to a representative.

 ***Other Applicable Laws**  
  The practices described above are in accordance with federal law. You may have other protections under applicable state laws, such as those in Vermont, California and Nevada. To the extent these state laws apply, we will comply with them when we share information about you. For example, Vermont law places additional limits on sharing information about Vermont residents. As long as they remain residents of Vermont, we will not share information we collect about Vermont residents to companies outside of Wachovia, except: 

  * To companies that perform marketing or other services on our behalf;
  * Contact information (like name and address), and transaction information (such as your payment history) to other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements;
  * With the authorization or consent of the Vermont resident; or
  * As permitted or required by law.

We also will not share credit information about Vermont residents received from others within Wachovia except with the authorization or consent of the Vermont resident.

Do Not Call Policy: This Privacy Statement constitutes Wachovia's Do Not Call Policy under the Telephone Consumer Protection Act for all consumers.

 _For Nevada residents:_ At any time, you may request to be placed on Wachovia's internal do not call list by following the instructions in the "Your Privacy Choices at Wachovia" section above. Nevada law also requires that we provide you with the following contact information:

| Wachovia Dealer Services  
Attention: TX5704  
PO Box 168048  
Irving, TX 75016|  | Bureau of Consumer Protection  
Office of the Nevada Attorney General  
555 E. Washington Street, Suite 3900  
Las Vegas, Nevada 89101  
Phone: 1-702-486-3132  
Email: [BCPINFO@ag.state.nv.us](mailto:BCPINFO@ag.state.nv.us)  
---|---|---  
  
 **You Choice to Limit Use of Information for Marketing**  
Wachovia is providing this notice.

You may limit Wachovia companies, such as the Wachovia banking, insurance and securities affiliates, Evergreen companies, American Mortgage Network, Inc. doing business as Vertice, GE Capital Administrative Services, Inc., GE Capital Management Corp., GE Capital Warranty Corp., Heritage Indemnity Company, Heritage Mechanical Breakdown Corp., J.L. Kaplan Associates, LLC, Metropolitan West Capital Management, LLC, Tattersall Advisory Group, Inc., Westlake Group Ltd., and Westlake Insurance Company, Ltd., from marketing their products or services to you based on credit or transaction information about you that they receive from other Wachovia companies. This information includes your account balance, payment history, and your credit history.

Your choice to limit such marketing offers from Wachovia companies will apply until you tell us to change your choice.

If you have already made a choice to limit such marketing offers from Wachovia companies, you do not need to act again.

To limit such marketing offers, contact us:

  * By telephone: Call Wachovia Dealer Services at 800-289-8004, Monday through Friday from 5 a.m. to 7 p.m. PT.

However, when you choose this option to limit the use of this information by other Wachovia companies to market their products and services to you, your choice does not apply to any Wachovia company that has an existing business relationship with you or where the use is otherwise permitted by law, including the use of information made available to that Wachovia company prior to October 1, 2008.1This Privacy Statement explains how we handle and protect information and replaces any Privacy Statements previously provided. The Privacy Statement applies only to consumers who are customers or former customers of Wachovia Dealer Services, Inc. and have established relationships with Wachovia Dealer Services in the United States. The policies and practices described in this Privacy Statement are subject to change, but we will notify you if there are significant changes. This Privacy Statement is issued as of January 2008.

* Links to third party sites are provided for your convenience. Such sites are not within our control and may not follow the same privacy, security or accessibility standards as ours. Wachovia neither endorses nor guarantees offerings of the third party providers, nor is Wachovia responsible for the security, content or availability of the third party sites, their partners, or advertisers.
